<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>On My Wavelength</title>
        <link>/index.html</link>
        <copyright>Riveen Kumanayaka All Rights Reserved</copyright>
        <language>en</language>
        <description>This is an aggregated RSS feed of all my publications.</description>
        <item>
            <title>Not All Men, But Always a Man</title>
            <description>Why more abusers are men than any other demographic.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.substack.com/p/not-all-men-but-always-a-man</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026</pubDate>
            <category>Substack</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>You Don't Come Closer</title>
            <description>It's a late November night at a cafe when the past decides to visit you. For your luck or
                            otherwise, there is someone to listen to you—someone that actually cares.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/you-dont-come-closer.html</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gen-AI is just a fancy bootlicker</title>
            <description>Making a set of equations write poetry is not just lazy, it's a betrayal to what human creativity is.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.substack.com/p/gen-ai-is-just-a-fancy-bootlicker</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025</pubDate>
            <category>Substack</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Nights Were Young</title>
            <description>Aragalaya ("Struggle") was one of the most pivotal events I have ever witnessed and taken part in. It was an experience of both pride and fear alike. Ousting a family of war criminals and thieves, along with the toxic political world they built, cost more than just sweat and tears.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/the-nights-were-young.html</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>I See Only You</title>
            <description>Grief and guilt breaks the soul of all affected by it. When the narrator accidentally kills
                            their partner, the guilt of it consumes them into an irreversible spiral.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/i-see-only-you.html</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Are Girl-Children Immoral and Dangerous Seductresses in Lolita?</title>
            <description>In Nabokov’s Lolita, readers are presented with Humbert Humbert, who grooms and eventually rapes Dolores Haze, his “Lolita”. Despite his regret of the “foul lust [he] had inflicted upon [her],” and Dr. John Ray’s denouncement of Humbert as “horrible [and] abject,” in the preface, the social perception of Dolores and the “girl-children” is far from being absolved.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/post/2025/08/girl-children-in-lolita.html</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025</pubDate>
            <category>Publications</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Implications of Buddhism on Political Systems</title>
            <description>Buddhism, the state religion of Sri Lanka, has remained entangled in all lives and institutions of Sri Lanka. Historically, royal patronage and religious loyalty have elevated Buddhism to a state of authority.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/post/2025/08/buddhism-in-sri-lanka.html</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025</pubDate>
            <category>Publications</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Authorial God Hypothesis</title>
            <description>God—in many belief systems and prominently, the Abrahamic tradition—is an omnipotent, omniscient, omnipresent, omnibenevolent, and perfect being. These faiths and beliefs also credit God for creating the universe and its inhabitants: us.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/post/2025/08/authorial-god-hypothesis.html</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025</pubDate>
            <category>Blog</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Paint My Skies With Yellow Sparks</title>
            <description>As someone who has lived through the end of a civil war, yet at great relative safety, it
                            was very easy to be disillusioned. The horror of war is not a myth, but many wish it was and
                            many think it is.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/paint-my-skies-with-yellow-sparks.html</link>
            <pubDate>10 May, 2025</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Maybe the Gods are Playing Cricket</title>
            <description>As a child, I liked to imagine the scary and loud thunderstorms were just cricket matches in
                            heaven. There was a sense of comfort in it, but also felt gross to be under the rain.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/maybe-the-gods-are-playing-cricket.html</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Crying Maiden</title>
            <description>When Prof. Senavitharana is gifted a mysterious painting of a crying maiden, he does not
                            believe the strange tale behind it. But when the tale comes alive to haunt him, he soon
                            realises his mistake.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/the-crying-maiden.html</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>50 Shades of Gender: Gender Complexity and a Post-Gender Society</title>
            <description>For much of recorded history, gender and sex were used interchangeably: male meant XY chromosomes and masculinity, and female meant XX chromosomes and femininity. However, modern gender has evolved into a broader and more nuanced spectrum.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/post/2025/04/fifty-shades-of-gender.html</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025</pubDate>
            <category>Blog</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Maybe in a Few Years</title>
            <description>Do ever think of your friends two minutes to midnight and only feel unreserved love for
                            those
                            idiots? Yeah, me too. This is for my goof balls (they'll hate me for calling them that).</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/maybe-in-a-few-years.html</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Laboratory life: my work experience week at BGS</title>
            <description>My week began with a welcome tour of the research facilities at BGS and, more specifically, the geochemistry laboratories. The team provided an introduction to the field of mass spectrometry and the use of isotopes in archaeological research.</description>
            <link>https://www.bgs.ac.uk/news/laboratory-life-my-work-experience-week-at-bgs/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024</pubDate>
            <category>Blog</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>why it matters to remember</title>
            <description>cecil richard’s under a star called sun is a reader-led short story about a narrator where “the trajectory of [his] ship is unchanging.” he (i like to see myself on the ship; you may too) recalls that coffee “never tastes as good as the ones you get from the cafes back home”.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/post/2024/08/why-it-matters-to-remember.html</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024</pubDate>
            <category>Blog</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>He Fought for You</title>
            <description>Mahmoud Darwish once wrote, "The wars will end and the leaders will shake hands, [...] I do
                            not
                            know who sold the homeland but I know who paid the price." This is for all those who paid
                            the price.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/he-fought-for-you.html</link>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Collided Galaxies</title>
            <description>Grief is often raw and remains a sad and tender reminder of the past. It is a soft ache that
                            refuses to go away. Maybe in this cosmic dance, you may see someone else's stars embedded in
                            your
                            galaxy.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/colliding-galaxies.html</link>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Summer Night Under the Moon</title>
            <description>The stars hide a grand secret we are too stupid to know. But does it ever matter? Does
                            anything
                            hold meaning when you're drunk with love and run over by her beauty?</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/a-summer-night-under-the-moon.html</link>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>#2: The Limit of Opinion Entitlement</title>
            <description>People are entitled to their opinions, but general consensus agree that there is a limit to it. However, what is this limit? Where does it begin, and where does it end? Who decides the limits?</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/podcast/player.html#2</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024</pubDate>
            <category>Podcast</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>#1: Social Media and the Whole Thing</title>
            <description>What does it take to be an influencer? And what role does the audience actually play within this system? Find out with us!</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/podcast/player.html#1</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024</pubDate>
            <category>Podcast</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cost of Living and University Choices</title>
            <description>This is a report I co-authored with Adam Runacres, Freya Neason, and Ismail Choudhury for
                            The Access Project. We conducted introductory research on the relationship between the
                            university choices of students and the economic background.</description>
            <link>https://theaccessproject.org.uk/2024/06/24/cost-of-living-university-choices-report/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024</pubDate>
            <category>Publications</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Masked Figures</title>
            <description>The pandemic, and the lonliness that stemmed from it, left a large imprint on all of us that survived it. This is for the horrors we all battled with ourselves, and fear during then.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/masked-figures.html</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024</pubDate>
            <category>Publications</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How to make a Debating Motion?</title>
            <description>So, what is a motion? Basically, it is the topic which the debate is about. There are two sides which would be arguing this (although there could be four teams, sometimes).</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/post/2024/05/how-to-make-a-debating-motion.html</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024</pubDate>
            <category>Debating</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Name I Didn't Think Of</title>
            <description>This is a story of a slow-burn on fast-forward. He is a Physicist and she is a
                            Philosopher, and they both end up finding that there's more that attracts than Gravity.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/a-name-i-didnt-think-of.html</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Death's Fear</title>
            <description>Death is though to be the ultimate villain, the ghost that haunts over our shoulders.
                            This is how death sees some people, and it's never about our pretty little lives.</description>
            <link>https://riveenk.github.io/publications/deaths-fear.html</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023</pubDate>
            <category></category>
        </item>

    </channel>

</rss>
